Hi guys, quarterly earnings are coming
and let's see which stocks can be
potentially traded as a
result of earnings.  So, here we have
created, guys, a very simple earnings
calendar.  Come here and see, here is
my earnings calendar.  And here we
can sort by earnings date.
Right?  So along with this, guys, I have opened
our dashboard of the builder,
you will get it here by going to Builder and
Simulator.  If you open the risk dashboard,
you will see your risk position wise here.  Right?  So let's
start from here.  Let's see that
come on friend, I have not entered any position in XID.
XID earnings are today.  Let's ignore this.  We are
releasing our first quarter earnings
today.  So let's ignore this.  We
want to see the second quarter earnings
as the second quarter results will
start coming after September.
Right?  So we have already created a position in TCS.  Let
TCS be.  Let
us see the next position.  Let's look at HCLT.
Let's look at HCL Tech.  So guys very
simple HCL Tech earnings are coming
in 19 days on 13th October 2025.  So let's come
here, we click on Trade
of HCL Tech and here we come to
Strategy Builder.  Right?  So look guys,
our earnings are on October 13th.  It is
also written here that
we have come to the events tab.  It is also written here
that HCL Tech's earnings are on 13th October.
So for us, the relevant expiry,
in which the earnings movement
is incorporated, becomes 28th October for us.
So remember guys, in the expiry
in which the event is there, this expiry
includes the event on 28th October
because my event is on 13th October.  So the
implied volatility or volatility of this expiry should be
equal to the
regular volatility of HCL Tech plus the
volatility that is going to occur in the event.
Okay, right?  So remember this formula guys.
So guys what is my regular volatility of
HCL Tech?  There can be many estimates for this also.  Let's
see what
we can use to estimate.  The
easiest estimate we
can use is, look friend, my
actual employed volatility is for that
expiry in which there are no earnings.
Right?  This is my 30th September.  So
according to this it is saying that the
applied volatility should be 21.5.  Ok?  So I
say let's assume this is my regular
volatility.  This could be one of my sources.
Right?  Which is the expiry month in
which there are no earnings.  Right?  Or there
is no event.  This one happened.  The second source I can think of is
realized volatility.  Okay, right
?  I say, okay brother, my 30 day realized
volatility is 21.99% which is close
to 21.5%,
okay?  My 60 day realized volatility is
19.67%
again in this range seven day realized
volatility is 19.32% in this way I can take the
realized volatility of any sampling period and
say.  Come on
man, this could be my regular
volatility.  This is also my estimate.  This
is my estimate.  Right guys?  So,
if you place a trade on this, then you should also have an
estimate as to
what is the regular volatility of HCL Tech?  So guys,
this is telling me that look,
if I say that my seven day realized vol
is 19.3%, for example, the volatility of the market at the
event of expiry is 24%.
Is 24.9%.  So on this basis it is
telling me that brother HCL, HCL Tech will
move 4% on the day of earnings.  He is
telling me this.  This
came out according to my formula.  Ok?  3.92%
means a move of ₹56 from ₹56 to ₹60 is what the
market is expecting in HCL Tech on the
day of earnings.  Ok?  So I
say, okay friend, I have an option
here, this is the market estimate guys.
In the market estimate I
can select which wall I want to
put.  But here I have the ability.
I can also enter my estimate.   Let's assume that I think
brother HCLT will
not move at all.  Maybe 15%
volatility will be its regular volatility.
Right?  And on this basis I say
implied move.  So for example, 4% of the market is
employing.  I say, okay
brother, it will move only 4%.  4.1% say it.
This is what will move the market.  So according to these parameters,
my expiry volatility
, my October volatility,
seems to me to be very expensive
because the market has quoted 24.9 and
according to my estimates it is 22.4.  So
here I came to know that the
market strategy is expensive and it
gave me a sell signal that brother you
can sell.  If I reverse this.
So I say that friend, just
recently Trump has said that brother,
we are increasing the price of H1B.  You will have to pay $0000 every
month.  Many people are saying that it is a
negotiating technique.  Now she will not stand any further.
In the court, but let's assume he
says the news will come tomorrow.  Now I'm doing
$5000.  So maybe HCL Tech will
move a little more.  In May, its regular
volatility is 25%.  Right?  If its
regular volatility is 25% and we feel
that the earnings have
moved 2-3% to 4% in the past earnings.  We assume that there has been a
4% move in May B2 earnings.
So on this basis, he told me
that the price of the market straddle,
which includes earnings at
expiry, the price of the straddle of that expiry has become
cheaper.  So this
gave me the signal to say bye.
Okay, right?  Guys, I personally have
no idea what the volatility of HCL Tech should be right now.
Regular volatility is what
we reset once guys.
So I have no idea
what the regular volatility should be for HCL Tech.   All
I can see right now is that its at
the money employed value is 21.5
and seven day realized value, basically my
option is expiring in 6 days.
Its implied vol is 21.5 and seven
day realized vol is 19.3.  So maybe I
feel that this is a bit expensive.
Right?  The market is a bit expensive.  Two
points expensive.  I feel like maybe that's the case.
I can say this on the basis of this data point.
Ok?  But if I take this data
point, 30 day data point
, then this market does not seem so expensive to me.
Right?  Because
its 30 day realized value has been 21.9%.  And
actual employed wall 21.5% there is
not much difference between these two.  Is it okay guys?
So I still don't have any opinion whether
HCL Tech is expensive or cheap.  Expiry
with before earnings or after earnings.  I don't have any
opinion right now.
Right?  What else can we see?  And we
can also come and see here, guys.  This
is our IVP IVR graph.
We can come here and see where HCL Tech is
living.  So if I click on it here,
I will see HCL Tech coming here.
Right?  So its IVP is
greater than 50.  IVR is less than 50.
So this means that the price here
typically indicates a minor spike
in IV after a sustained period of low
volatility.  So this minor spike can come as a
result of earnings.  Yes Earnings
Date has been released.  One thing we found out was this.
In this we are using Guys 30 Day Constant
Maturity.
We are calculating this based on one year look back.
Right?  So, firstly we came to know that
earnings have come due to which there has been a
slight spike in the volume.  But naturally there was a
spike in earnings.  There has been a spike in volatility.
This means that the
market also expects that the
stock will move in earnings.  Right?
That's why there was a spike in volatility.
Spike didn't come for such fun.  The second thing
we can see is that there was a sustained period of low
volatility.  So here we can say
that friend, it means it is written here that
take the premium still relatively.  Buyers are
expecting further increase in IV
and why is this premium relatively low?
Because my IVP is greater than 50 but
IVR is less than 50.  Right?  So
coming here we can actually see that whatever has been the
range of my IV, obviously there was such a
major spike in IV during Trump time.
That's why my IVR is
appearing less to me.  But actually there is not that much lace.  It should
probably be here.
If I remove this Trump move, then
most likely this
HCL Tech will reach here.
Which is high IV and IVR.  Right?  So
again its volatility seems high.  Okay, right
?  Which is the 30 day volatility that
encapsulates both these periods.  On that
basis, volatility seems high.  So
I don't see any clear cut trade
here.  But if I have to take a trade,
what trade can I take?  So
maybe guys, we can do this, I assume, let's buy a strudel
for earnings.  I would
not place this trade behind earnings.
Maybe
I'll square it off the day before earnings.  But my
expectation is that this implied
volatility will not fall.  Because as we get closer
and closer to earnings,
my regular days are decreasing.  The
weightage of the end earnings day is increasing
in my volatility calculations.  Right?  This
is simple maths guys.  So on this basis
I say, come on friend, I have not received any clear cut buy
or sell signal.  But for
now this is a risky trade guys.
So I am not recommending you take this trade.
But I will take this trade just for education purpose.
ok sir.  We
call this HCL Tech Under Earnings.
Come here.  We select the mid price
here.  And let's place all
orders.   I have put
simple here.  Now let's look
ahead in a while.  See next stock
any.  ICICI LBRD General Insurance Company.   Let's
see this.  This is the last updated meaning
we only found out yesterday that its earnings date has
come.  Come on guys let's click on trade it.
Guys, we have come here,
we will see the earnings of ICICI GI in ICICI LBD,
guys.  It is happening on 14th October which is the
expiry after September and the
expiry in October.  But here guys
my options are quite illiquid.
Look here, 1880 is my at the money strike,
here 58 at 62 my BASC is
placed here.  End 52 is fine.  I would be like ₹2
de dunga main Bask spread me just to see
ke yaar order jaata tha nahi.  But let's
evaluate it here once, guys.
My expiry volatility between 23 and 24
is event volatility.  And here
we will see that it is showing me 22.
So there is not much difference.  There
is a difference of one wall point here.   There
is a difference of one vol point between expiry volatility versus non-expiry volatility.  And if we look here, my
30 day realized value is 19.9.  60
Days is 19.7
Days is 12.9 Which is quite low.  Right?
We can confirm this here also.
ICICI ICICI GI in VRP dashboard
here comes my ICICI
GI.  So here we can see that Guys
IV is a little high.  Relative
to realized volatility integrated RVs
always use.  We will come and
see first.  So guys, it seems to me
that relative to the
realized volume, it seems a little overpriced.  Let us
check once we come here.
ICICI GI ICICI LBRD I am
feeling low here.  Volatility relative to its own
history.  Right?  So
here you might feel that on the basis of this, he is
telling me that relative to its own one
year history, it seems low.  But
if I come here and see, then the
history of Yes IV has been above 25 in the history.
It's below 25 right now.  It's
around 23.  But the Realize Wall is currently running low.
Right?  19 Is My 30 Day Realize Vol.
And here we will see that my 30 day
stock has run away.  Let's take this one again.  After
modifying, we
come to mid.  These market makers are looting me at mid-price.
Anyway we come back to ICICI GI.
So here we see guys that
relative to the realized volatility, it is
running a little expensive.  Isn't it?  And this is what
we saw
here also my Seven Day Realize Wall is
very low.  Is 12.9.  Right?  So here
I can think that hey there was a
delay in speaking.  From 22 it suddenly came down to 20.
This has come down from 22 to 20.  And it's
showing me 23 versus 19.  Of
course, it has 30 day constant maturity, so
earnings are also coming in it.  If I have to
take an opinion guys, then
this volatility seems a bit expensive to me,
relative to here we can
see that my realized value is 19.9%
and my seven day realized value is even
lower.  Right?  When I go to events,
my seven day realization wall is 12%.   I
say, okay brother, let's sell this straddle,
then we will use it against it, I will take
a strangle
here, if I am confident
that the volatility will increase further, the implied
war will increase further as a result of earnings, then
I say here, okay friend,
instead of one lot, I will take two lots, I
sold one lot here, took two lots and
live trade, okay brother, done.  On this we say
ICICI
earnings
confirmed.
We place orders at its mid price.
You will also have to give some task spread like ₹1 ₹2.
You are trading long-term options.  If
you are trading in the next month then you can
apply for options guys.
Place orders.  Let's see whether we get something or not.
Look here guys,
my HCL Tech trade has been executed.
So here I will now
see the risk in the dashboard.  Go to the Risk Dashboard.   Let's go
to the Risk Dashboard.  And let's see here.  Let us
refresh the
risk dashboard once.  So
guys, here I am, this is my position in HCL Tech.
Here comes HCL Tech earnings
where I can see its Greeks.
I can also see my unit exposure.
And
here comes my second ICICI Lo LBAD
position.  This position has also opened up.
I can see it here now.  Hey, my trade is
not complete.  Right now my delta is
showing 150.  Meaning that one of my orders
remained naked.  That's my putt that I had to buy.
I had to buy two lots of put.
He is still naked with me.  Good sir.  If the
market goes down, I will
not get the put.  I say okay sir.  Come on,
I have become the best bit.  I will cancel this once.  Let's try
cancelling it.
I want to buy two 1880s.  Ok.
Come here and buy two pieces.  Let's take a putt.  Bye first.  Bye.   Try
taking a putt.  I've done mid-market.
Meaning I am paying up a little.
it gave me a put.  Let's
come here.  Pick up another putt.  Try to
lift another putt.  If LTP is not updated
then it is wrong guys.  This is an illiquid option,
guys.  So see how much effort is required to
place a trade.  Should I pick up another one
?  Let's pick up another one.  We pick up only the two things we
wanted to pick up.  And here
my
mid price is 49
4890 my mid price has increased a little more.
Come on guys, let's pick this one up too.
This has also come to me.  Okay guys?  So here
I have now created two positions guys.
I have made this after taking some opinion on the earnings of both.  Guys, by doing this we
can create more positions.  Right?  With
regards to earnings.  As the stock
earnings and dates get released,
we will start showing up those stocks here.
And here we can basically
form opinions.  This is done by
using dashboards.  Right?  You can also use
this dashboard of events that we have created using dashboards, this
event cocktail that we have created, on its
basis.
Using this you can decide whether
we should take trade in earnings or
not.  Ok?  Thank you guys.